[柯克] 舰长日志，星历5718.3
[Kirk] Captain's Log : Star date 5718.3.
企业号正在绕着厄尔巴二号飞行，这是一颗大气有毒的行星…
The Enterprise is orbiting Elba 11, a planet with a poisonous atmosphere ...
联邦在此建立了一个收容所
where the Federation maintains an asylum...
收治了银河系中少数几个不可救药的犯罪狂人
for the few remaining incorrigible, criminally insane of the galaxy.
我们正在为他们带来革命性的新药
We are bringing a revolutionary new medicine to them,
联邦希望用它永久消除…
a medicine with which the Federation hopes to eliminate mental illness...
精神疾病
for all time.
我正和史波克先生一起传送下去
I am transporting down with Mr. Spock,
把药送给唐纳德·科里医生
and we're delivering the medicine to Dr. Donald Cory,
他是殖民地主管
the governor of the colony.
我是唐纳德，很高兴见到你
Donald, good to see you.
主管
Governor.
先生们，你们不知道我有多开心
Gentlemen, you don't know what a treat this is for me.
我已经很久没有访客了，吉姆
It's been too long since I've had company, Jim.
力场恢复原位
The force field's back in place now.
这意味着你俩被困在这里了
That means you two are trapped here.
我不接受你不和我一起吃饭的借口
I'm not accepting any excuses for your not dining with me.
我们会很高兴的
We'd be delighted.
主管，自从我们上次访问以后，你又收治了一名病人
Governor, you indicated one additional inmate since our last visit,
总共15个，对吗？
making a total of 15. Is it correct?
是的
It is.
康复计划进展得不太好
The rehabilitation program isn't progressing too well,
我怀疑这种药的有效性
and I have my doubts about the effectiveness of this medicine too.
唐纳德，你变成悲观主义者了吗？
Donald, are you becoming a pessimist?
我恐怕是的
I'm afraid I have.
数十亿人里总共有15个无法治愈的疯子…
A total of 15 incurably insane out of billions...
要我说并不多
is not what I would call an excessive figure.
新病人是谁？
Who is the new inmate?
呃，加斯
Uh, Garth.
[科里] 伊扎尔的加斯
[Cory] Garth of Izar,
一位以前的星际舰队舰长
a former star ship fleet captain.
当我还是学院的学员时，他的功绩是必读的
When I was a cadet at the academy, his exploits were required reading.
他是我的英雄之一，我想见他
He was one of my heroes. I'd like to see him.
当然
Of course.
[开门]
[Door Opens]
[咔嗒声]
[Click]
舰长！
Captain!
你正在犯一个错误
You're making a mistake.
柯克舰长时间紧迫，玛塔
Captain Kirk is pressed for time at the moment, Marta.
我没有什么问题！
There's nothing the matter with me!
你不能看着我就明白吗？你不能通过听来判断吗？
Can't you see just by looking at me? Can't you tell by listening?
她听起来很理性，舰长
She sounds rational enough, Captain.
我是理性的
I am rational.
你想告诉我什么？
What is it you want to tell me?
我不能在他面前告诉你
I can't tell you in front of him.
你害怕在科里主管面前说话？
You're afraid to talk in front of Governor Cory?
他根本不是真的科里主管，就是这样
He isn't really Governor Cory at all, that's just it.
[轻笑] 这几天她一直在说
[Chuckles] She's been saying that for days now.
我们的医务人员无法弄清楚原因[轻笑]
Our medical staff can't figure out why. [Chuckles]
这是加斯
Here's Garth.
他异常不安
He's been unusually disturbed,
我们不得不施加额外的限制
and we've had to impose additional restraint.
科里？
Cory?
[呼气]
[Exhales]
是的，吉姆，我是科里
Yes, Jim, I'm Cory.
[疯狂地笑]
[Laughing Maniacally]
这是真的，他骗了你
It's true. He tricked you.
[笑]
[Laughing]
[咔嗒声]
[Click]
你说你想见我，舰长，嗯，我在这里
You said you wanted to see me, Captain. Well, here I am.
[加斯笑]
[Garth Laughing]
[柯克] 宇宙，最后的边疆
[Kirk] Space, the final frontier.
这些是星舰企业号的航程
These are the voyages of the star ship Enterprise.
它的五年任务：探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: to explore strange new worlds,
寻找新生命和新文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇踏前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
上帝毁灭之人
Whom Gods Destroy
你的瓦肯朋友还活着，舰长
Your Vulcan friend is still alive, Captain.
我的相位枪设置为击晕，而不是击杀
My phaser was set to stun, not to kill.
他会很舒服
He'll be quite comfortable,
几乎和你以及我们尊敬的主管一样舒适
almost as comfortable as you and our esteemed governor.
加斯，必须让他受罪吗？
Garth, do you have to make him suffer like that?
用我的正式头衔称呼我，柯克
You will address me by my proper title, Kirk.
对不起，我应该说加斯舰长
I'm sorry. I should've said Captain Garth.
我是加斯勋爵，以前是伊扎尔的
I am Lord Garth, formerly of Izar,
我领导着宇宙未来的主人
and I lead the future masters of the universe.
对不起，加斯勋爵
I'm sorry, Lord Garth.
你们地球人是一群顽固的人，不是吗？
You Earth people are a stiff-necked lot, aren't you?
放开他
Release him.
恐怕打倒你还不够
I'm afraid that subjugating you won't be enough.
你必须被监禁
You must be confined.
以及银河系所有不屈服于我的意志的的人
And all the people of the galaxy who will not bow to my will...
都必须被监禁或毁灭
must be confined or destroyed.
加斯舰长，听我说
Captain Garth, listen to me.
嗬嗬！我们敬爱的主管决定向我们发表讲话
Ho-ho! Our beloved governor has decided to address us,
我们还没有允许他说话
and we have not given him our permission to speak.
你这么怕他，以至于你必须让他闭嘴？
Are you so afraid of him that you must keep him pinned?
[咔嗒声]
[Click]
我不怕任何人，你们都没有力量反对我
I'm afraid of no one. You're all powerless against me.
谢谢，你对药做了什么？
Thank you.
你对药做了什么？
What've you done with the medicine?
药？
The medicine?
你是说毒药，我摧毁了它
You mean the poison. I destroyed it.
毁了？
Destroyed it?
这是你唯一的希望
It was your only hope!
安静！
Silence!
弱者的喋喋不休让我厌烦
The chatter of inferior weaklings wearies me.
是时候我来接管企业号了，当然，你会帮助我的
And it's time I took command of the Enterprise. You'll help me, of course.
当然
Of course.
我的船员叛变了
My crew mutinied.
首先我要用企业号去追捕
The first use I will make of the Enterprise is to hunt them down...
并惩罚他们
and punish them for that.
企业号的船员也会叛变
The crew of the Enterprise will also mutiny.
[轻笑] 但他们不会
[Chuckles] But they won't.
你看，舰长，我掌握了一个有用的技巧
You see, Captain, there's a helpful technique I've mastered.
[笑]
[Laughing]
再见，亲爱的，我会想念你
Good-bye, darling. I'll miss you.
[咔嗒声]
[Click]
科里主管，你感觉如何？
Governor Cory, how do you feel?
好的，我们任何人都没有办法
All right. There is no help for any of us...
如果那个疯子是企业号的指挥官
if that madman is in command of the Enterprise.
他吹嘘自己创造了宇宙中最强大的爆炸物
He boasts that he's created the most powerful explosive in the universe,
我相信他
and I believe him.
他是如何随意变换形态的？
How does he manage to change form at will?
安托斯人教他细胞变形技术
The people of Antos taught him the techniques of cellular metamorphosis...
来修复他身体被毁坏的部分
to restore the destroyed parts of his body.
后来他自己学会了用这种技术
By himself, he later learned to use the technique...
把自己变成他想要的任何样子
to recreate himself into any form he wished.
我们第一次知道是当一名警卫
The first time we knew about it was when a guard,
在加斯的牢房里看到了以为是我的人，然后放了他
seeing what he thought was me in Garth's cell, released him.
他真是个天才，多么浪费
He was such a genius. What a waste.
力场开启，好的
Force field is off. Good.
在我下达命令之前，留在这里不要被人看到
Remain here out of sight until I give the order to join me.
[控制台哔哔声]
[Console Beeping]
柯克呼叫企业号
Kirk to Enterprise.
我是斯科特，长官
Scott here, sir.
传送我上船
Beam me aboard.
是的，长官，女王到女王三级
Aye, sir. Queen to queen's level three.
我说了传送我上船
I said beam me aboard.
我说女王到女王三级
I said, queen to queen's level three.
我们没有时间解决国际象棋问题，传送我上船
We have no time for chess problems. Beam me aboard!
我正在遵守你的命令，舰长，女王到女王三级
I'm following your orders, Captain. Queen to queen's level three.
只是测试，稍后与你联系
Just testing. Be in touch with you later.
不！
No!
[呻吟]
[Moaning]
哦！
Oh!
[尖叫]
[Screaming]
我给了他暗号，他为什么不给我暗号？
I gave him the sign. Why didn't he give me the countersign?
有问题
Something's wrong.
用国际象棋问题是舰长自己的建议
Using the chess problem was the captain's own suggestion.
他不可能忘记，我不相信他在测试我
He couldn't have forgotten it, and I can't believe he was testing me.
上尉，重新建立通讯
Lieutenant, re-establish communication.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
[哔哔声]
[Beeping]
没有回应，斯科特先生
There's no response, Mr. Scott.
立刻派一支武装特遣队去传送室
Send an armed detail to the transporter room immediately.
是的，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
苏鲁先生
Mr. Sulu,
你的传感器显示什么？
what do your sensors show?
我们不能传送任何人下去，一个力场正在运行
We can't beam anybody down. The force field is in full operation,
并且所有进入庇护所的交通方式都被封锁了
and all forms of transport into the asylum dome are blocked off.
那我们可以炸开一条通过力场的路
Well, we could blast our way through the field,
但冒着摧毁船长，史波克先生…
but only at the risk of destroying the captain, Mr. Spock...
和厄尔巴二号上其他生物的风险
and any other living thing on Elba ll.
我们为何强大到足以毁灭一个星球…
How can we be powerful enough to wipe out a planet...
却还是那么无助？
and still be so helpless?
我们将带走企业号
We are going to take the Enterprise,
你听到我了吗？
do you hear me?
我们要带走她…
We are going to take her...
哪怕我得打碎柯克舰长身上的每一根骨头
if I have to shatter every bone in Captain Kirk's body.
舰长？
Captain?
柯克舰长？
Captain Kirk?
我希望你没有很难受，舰长
I hope you haven't been too uncomfortable, Captain.
我感谢你的关心
Thank you for your concern.
总的来说，还是比较安逸的
All in all, it's been rather restful.
好的
Good.
不过，作为东道主，我恐怕还是失职了
Still, I've been quite remiss in my duties as your host.
你可能记得我确实邀请你吃饭了
I did invite you to dinner, as you may recall.
我忘记了
I've forgotten.
但我没有
But I haven't.
你和史波克先生会是我的客人
You and Mr. Spock are to be my guests.
史波克先生在哪里？
Where is Mr. Spock?
就在这儿，玛塔！
Right here. Marta!
为什么我不能只炸掉他的一只耳朵？
Why can't I blow off Just one of his ears?
别闹了，史波克先生会认为我们不热情好客的
Stop that, Marta. Mr. Spock will think we're lacking in hospitality.
你不加入我们吗，舰长？
Won't you join us, Captain?
你好吗，史波克先生？
How are you, Mr. Spock?
确实很好，谢谢，舰长
Very well, indeed. Thank you, Captain.
科里主管不加入我们吗？
Isn't Governor Cory joining us?
主管似乎不在客人名单上
The governor doesn't seem to be on the guest list.
哦？疏忽？
Oh? An oversight?
有意的，呃，主管在禁食
An intentional one. Uh, the governor's fasting.
那样的话，我们必须谢绝
In that case, we must decline with thanks.
呃，舰长
Uh, Captain.
别傻了，吉姆，跟着他走
Don't be a fool, Jim. Go along with him.
好建议，主管，嗯，舰长？
Good advice, Governor. Well, Captain?
你会发现我们摆了一张漂亮的桌子
You'll find we set a handsome table.
而且表演非常有趣
And the entertainment is most enjoyable.
你很会说服人
You're very persuasive.
对，我当然是
Yes, I am. I certainly am.
咦 哈！
Yah-haw!
[全笑]
[Laughter]
[笑]
[Laughing]
你的手别碰柯克！
Keep your hands off Kirk!
你这个花心的东西！  [笑]
You treacherous thing! [Laughing]
你嫉妒了
You're jealous!
我才不是那种人
I am above that sort of thing.
你的殷勤惹恼了舰长，仅此而已
The captain is annoyed by your attentions, that's all.
亲爱的，我惹恼你了吗？
Am I annoying you, dearest?
呃，并没有
Uh, not really.
[轻笑]
[Chuckles]
他觉得我很迷人，而你对此很不安，承认吧
He finds me fascinating and you're bothered by it. Admit it.
我可以把你打死
I may have you beaten to death.
不，你不会的
No, you won't,
因为我是这个星球上最美丽的女人
because I am the most beautiful woman on this planet.
你是唯一的女人，你这蠢婆娘
You're the only woman on this planet, you stupid cow.
嗯，我是这个星系里最美丽的女人！
Well, I'm the most beautiful woman in this galaxy!
你令人厌恶！
You're repulsive!
我很美丽！
I'm beautiful!
而且我也很聪明
And I'm intelligent too.
我写诗
I write poetry,
我画绝美的图画
and I paint marvellous pictures.
而且我是一个很棒的舞者
And I am a wonderful dancer.
胡说，一派胡言！
Lies! All lies!
你是我见过的最大的骗子
You are the greatest liar I have ever met!
让我听一首你写的诗
Let me hear one poem you've written.
如你所愿
If you like.
[轻声地] 舰长，如果你能转移注意力
[Softly] Captain, if you could create a diversion,
我也许能找到控制室并打开力场
I might be able to find the control room and open the forcefield.
我们只需要几秒钟，如果斯科提已经通知了警卫
All we need is a few seconds, if Scotty has alerted security.
先生们，尊重一下演员
Gentlemen, courtesy for the performer.
“我怎么能够把你来比作夏天？
"Shall I compare thee to a summer's day?
“你不独比它可爱也比它温婉
"Thou art more lovely and more temperate.
“狂风把五月宠爱的娇蕊作践
"Rough winds do shake the darling buds of May,
夏天出赁的期限…”
and summer's lease hath all... "
你写的？
You wrote that?
昨天，事实上
Yesterday, as a matter of fact.
它是一位名叫莎士比亚的地球人写的…
It was written by an Earth man named Shakespeare...
很久以前！
a long time ago!
这并没有改变我昨天又写了一遍的事实
Which does not alter the fact that I wrote it again yesterday!
我认为这是我最好的诗之一，不是吗？
I think it's one of my best poems, don't you?
我可以赤手空拳地杀了你！
I may kill you with my bare hands!
啊！
Aah!
事实上，舰长，她是个一流的舞者
Actually, Captain, she is a superb dancer.
玛塔，亲爱的，你不为我们的客人跳舞吗？
Marta, my dear, won't you dance for our guests?
那不是请求
That was not a request.
她太棒了，不是吗，舰长？
Marvellous, isn't she, Captain?
是的，呃…难以置信
Yes, uh... incredible.
史波克先生，你有什么感觉？
What is your reaction, Mr. Spock?
我觉得，呃…
I find it, uh...
它有点有趣和怀旧
mildly interesting and somewhat nostalgic,
如果你能理解我的意思
if I understand the use of that word.
怀旧？
Nostalgic?
是的，它有点让人想起
Yes. It is somewhat reminiscent of the dances...
瓦肯小孩在幼儿园跳的舞蹈
that Vulcan children do in nursery school.
当然，孩子们不是那么地…
Of course, the children are not so...
协调
well-coordinated.
[鼓掌]
[Applause]
如果你想，她是你的了
She's yours if you wish, Captain.
哦，呃…谢谢
Oh, uh... thank you.
那个…你很宽宏大量
That's, um... very magnanimous of you.
你会发现我对朋友慷慨，对敌人无情
You'll find that I am magnanimous to my friends and merciless to my enemies.
我希望你们都成为我的朋友
And I want both of you to be my friends.
我们的友谊究竟建立在什么基础上？
On what, precisely, is our friendship to be based?
嗯，在最坚实的基础上，史波克先生，开明的自我利益
Well, upon the firmest of foundations, Mr. Spock, enlightened self-interest.
舰长，你是银河系仅次于我的
You, Captain, are second only to me...
最优秀的军事指挥官
as the finest military commander in the galaxy.
受宠若惊
That's very flattering.
我现在主要是一名探险家，加斯舰长
I am primarily an explorer now, Captain Garth.
我也是，我绘制的新世界地图比历史上任何人都多
And so have I been. I have charted more new worlds than any man in history.
并试图摧毁安托斯四号，为什么？
And tried to destroy Antos IV. Why?
我能说是因为他们对联邦怀有敌意
Well, I could say because they were actively hostile to the Federation.
是的，你能说，但那不是事实
Yes, you could say, but that would be untrue.
同意[轻笑]
Agreed. [Chuckles]
实际上，他们是相当无恶意的
Actually, they were quite harmless,
在我受伤将死时，他们让我变得完整
and they made me whole when I was maimed and dying.
出于感激之情，我给了他们一个星系
And in my gratitude, I offered them the galaxy.
他们拒绝了我，我判处他们死刑
They rejected me, and I condemned them to death.
作为星际舰队的舰长
How could you, a star ship fleet captain,
你怎么会认为联邦船员…
believe that a Federation crew...
会盲目听从你的命令毁灭整个安托斯种族
would blindly obey your order to destroy the entire Antos race,
一个以追求仁爱和平著称的民族？
a people famous for their benevolence and peaceful pursuits?
那是我唯一失算的！
That was my only miscalculation!
我变了
I had changed!
我已经克服了这堕落的弱点…
I had risen above this decadent weakness...
顺便说一下，它仍然由你指挥，舰长
which still has you in its command, by the way, captain.
不包括我的船员，我无法左右他们
My crew had not. I couldn't sway them.
但我的新船员，这个房间里的人
But my new crew, the men in this room,
将毫无疑问地服从我的命令
will obey my orders without question.
先生们
Gentlemen,
你们有眼睛，但你们看不见
you have eyes but you cannot see.
星系围绕着我们
Galaxies surround us,
无限远景
limitless vistas!
然而，联邦会让我们
And yet the Federation would have us grub away...
像蚂蚁一样
like some ants on some...
在比平常大一点的蚁丘上翻掘
somewhat larger than usual anthill!
但我不是昆虫
But I am not an insect!
我是宇宙的主人，我必须申明我的主权
I am master of the universe, and I must claim my domain.
我同意战争曾经是必要的
I agree there was a time when war was necessary,
而你是我们最伟大的战士
and you were our greatest warrior.
我在校时研究过你在阿克纳的胜利
I studied your victory at Axanar when I was a cadet.
实际上，现在仍是学院的必读内容
In fact, it's still required reading.
也应该是
As well it should be.
很好
Very well.
但我第一次访问阿克纳是作为一名执行和平任务的学员
But my first visit to Axanar was as a new-fledged cadet on a peace mission.
和平任务！政客和弱者！
Peace mission! Politicians and weaklings!
他们是人道主义者和政治家，他们有一个梦想…
They were humanitarians and statesmen, and they had a dream...
梦想成为了现实并在星球间传播
a dream that became a reality and spread throughout the stars,
这个梦想让史波克先生和我成为了兄弟
a dream that made Mr. Spock and me brothers.
史波克先生，你认为柯克舰长和你自己是兄弟吗？
Mr. Spock, do you consider Captain Kirk and yourself brothers?
柯克舰长说话有些形象化
Captain Kirk speaks somewhat figuratively...
情绪过度激动
and with undue emotion:
然而，他说的是合乎逻辑的
however, what he says is logical...
我确实同意
and I do, in fact, agree with it.
[笑] 瞎了！
[Laughing] Blind!
真是瞎了眼！
Truly blind!
柯克舰长是你的指挥官！
Captain Kirk is your commanding officer!
而史波克先生，你是他的下属，仅此而已
You are his subordinate and that is all.
然而，史波克先生，你本身就是一位值得称道的指挥官
Yet, Mr. Spock, you are a worthy commander in your own right,
在我的舰队中，你肯定能指挥一艘星舰
and in my fleet you will surely have a star ship to command.
请原谅我，但你的舰队究竟在哪里？
Please forgive me, but exactly where is your fleet?
在那里等我
Out there waiting for me.
他们有充分的理由拥护我的事业
They will flock to my cause, and for good reason.
无限权力，无限财富
Limitless power! Limitless wealth.
由精英统治的太阳系
And solar systems ruled by the elite.
先生们，我们是精英，我们必须拿走我们理应拥有的东西
We, gentlemen, are that elite, and we must take what is rightfully ours...
从现在持有它的颓废弱者手中
from the decadent weaklings that now hold it.
加斯舰长…
Captain Garth...
加斯勋爵！
Lord Garth!
如你所愿
As you wish.
无论如何，你必须意识到这个事实…
At any rate, you must be aware of the fact...
你正试图重现灾难…
that you are attempting to recreate the disaster...
上次这么做让你成为了这个地方的病人
which resulted in your becoming an inmate in this place.
我被背叛了，受到了野蛮的对待
I was betrayed and treated barbarically.
你受到了正义和同情的对待
You were treated with justice and with compassion,
而你对待你的受害者则相反
which you failed to show towards any of your intended victims.
从逻辑上讲，因此，人们必须承担…
Logically, therefore, one must assume...
带走这只动物！
Remove this animal!
尝尝这酒，舰长
Try some of this wine, Captain.
它有一种浓郁，醇厚的风味，能让人感觉愉悦
It has a robust, full-bodied flavour which you'll find diverting.
不，谢谢，我宁愿加入史波克先生
No, thank you. I prefer to join Mr. Spock.
我想要你留在这里
And I prefer that you remain here.
玛塔，亲爱的
Marta, my dear.
我们觉得你的表演很迷人，不是吗，舰长？
We found your little divertissement enchanting, didn't we, Captain?
但后面还有，活动才刚刚开始
But there's more to come. The entertainment has merely begun.
顺便说一下，我猜你会下棋
By the way, I assume you play chess.
偶尔
Occasionally.
我也是，你会如何回应女王到女王三级
So do l. How would you respond to queen to queen's level three?
我相信你知道有无限种反击
I'm sure you're aware that there are an infinite number of countermoves.
我只对一个感兴趣
I'm interested in only one.
拼了老命我也想不到是哪一个？
I can't for the life of me imagine which one.
“拼了老命”是个好选择
"For the life of me" is a phrase well chosen.
可能会到那个地步
It could literally come to that.
我死了对你没好处
Dead I am of no use to you.
但我能让你渴望死亡，乞求死亡
But I can make you long for death, beg for death.
“在十一月的午夜，当死人集市临近
"In the midnight of November, when the dead man's fare is nigh,
“山谷中充满危险，天空中布满愤怒”
and the danger in the valley, and the anger in the sky."
我今天早上写的，你喜欢吗？
I wrote that this morning. Do you like it?
是的，我认为它非常好
Yes, I think it's very good.
[轻声] 告诉他他想知道的
[Softly] Tell him what he wants to know.
我们就一起走
We'll go away together.
[低语] 我不能
[Whispering] I can't.
但你一定要，我求你
But you must. I beg of you.
哦，不要乞求，玛塔！这是有辱人格的
Oh, don't beg, Marta! It's degrading.
女王到女王三级，舰长？
Queen to queen's level three, Captain.
你很快就会
You'll talk freely...
畅所欲言的
and quite soon.
舰长，在你面前的
What you see before you, Captain,
是我的最新发明
is my latest invention.
外表普通，近乎原始，你说是不是？
Quite ordinary in appearance, almost primitive, wouldn't you say?
是的，我认得
Yes, I recognize it.
它用于康复目的
It's used for rehabilitation purposes.
它帮助许多人恢复健康
It helped many men back to health.
外表有欺骗性
Appearances can be deceiving.
曾经它是康复过程的
Once it was a part of the rehabilitation process,
一部分，其本身是不痛的
and as such, quite painless.
而且，我也可以说是无用的
And I might add useless too.
它让人变得温顺，对我毫无用处
It made men docile and of no use to me.
我对超声波的使用进行了一些改进
I've added certain refinements to the use of ultrasonic waves.
椅子不再是无痛的
The chair is no longer painless.
把主管放上去
Put the governor in it.
女王到女王三级，柯克舰长？
Queen to queen's level three, Captain Kirk?
事实上，它极度痛苦
It is, in fact, exquisitely painful,
正如你将看到的
as you will now see.
[尖锐的嗡嗡声]
[High-Pitched Whirring]
[科里呻吟]
[Cory Groaning]
真有趣，不是吗？
Interesting, isn't it?
疼痛是真实的，可以无限地延长
The pain is real and can be prolonged indefinitely,
因为没有组织破坏
because there is no actual destruction of tissue.
住手！
Stop it!
[嗡嗡声停止]
[Whirring Stops]
当然，舰长，只要你开口
Of course, Captain. You have but to ask.
现在，如你所见，他没有受到身体伤害
Now, as you can see, he has not been harmed physically,
然而，对极度折磨的记忆仍然存在
yet the memory of the exquisite torment remains.
女王到女王三级，舰长？
Queen to queen's level three, Captain.
不
No.
真遗憾
Too bad.
带走我们尊贵的主管
Remove our distinguished governor.
把柯克舰长放在椅子上
Put Captain Kirk in the chair.
不，你不能那样做！
No, you mustn't do that!
你对我越来越冒犯了，亲爱的
You really are becoming offensive to me, my dear.
不要逼我把你放进去
Don't make it necessary for me to put you in it.
[尖锐的嗡嗡声]
[High-Pitched Whirring]
女王到女王三级，柯克舰长？
Queen to queen's level three, Captain Kirk.
请住手！
Please, stop it!
你想要他，不是吗？
You want him, don't you?
是的  非常想加入他吗？
Yes. Badly enough to join him?
听我说，我的加斯勋爵
Listen to me, my Lord Garth.
我可以让他告诉我你想知道的
I can get him to tell me what you want to know.
让你试试可能会很有趣
Might be interesting to have you try.
[嗡嗡声停止]
[Whirring Stops]
[呼气]
[Exhales]
没有突破？  没有， 斯科特先生
No breakthrough? No, Mr. Scott.
仍然没有来自这个星球的回应
Still no response from the planet.
传感器读数？
Sensor readings?
星球远端的力场最弱
The force field is weakest on the far side of the planet.
我们可以派一个小队
We can send down a shuttlecraft
穿着环境装置乘穿梭机下去
carrying a team in environmental suits.
没有用的，斯科提
It won't work, Scotty.
他们必须在有毒的大气中跋涉数千英里
They'd have to cover thousands of miles through poisonous atmosphere...
在他们到达收容所前
before they'd ever reach the asylum.
是的，你是对的，即使他们成功了，他们无法携带任何强力的东西
Aye, you're right. Even if they made it, they couldn't carry anything powerful enough...
冲破收容所的防护罩
to break through the asylum dome.
只有船本身才能做到
Only the ship herself could do that.
可能会杀了吉姆和史波克
Probably kill Jim and Spock.
医生，他们可能已经死了
Doctor, they may already be dead.
慢慢来，亲爱的
Slowly, darling.
慢慢地
Slowly.
休息
Rest.
这更多的是加斯的游说吗，玛塔？
Is this more of Garth's persuasion, Marta?
我告诉他我会找到你的秘密
I told him I'd discover your secret.
我撒了谎
I lied.
我会告诉他任何事情来拯救你免受那种折磨
I would have told him anything to save you from that torment.
我相信你说的是实话
I believe you mean that.
我是的
I do.
哦
Oh.
这是我一直渴望的地方
This is where I've longed to be.
我想从我第一次见到你的那一刻起，我就知道我爱你
I think I knew I loved you from the moment I first saw you.
玛塔
Marta.
Marta,
我可以帮你
I can help you,
但我必须回到企业号才可以
but I must get to the Enterprise to do that.
那是不可能的
That's not possible.
哦，不，可能的
Oh, yes, it is.
如果我能到达控制室…
It is. If I can get to the control room...
并移除力场，那么加斯就完了
and remove the force field, then Garth is finished.
加斯是我的领袖
Garth is my leader.
他会带你走向毁灭
He will lead you to destruction.
他…
He's...
已经毁掉了本可以帮助你的药物
already destroyed the medicine that could have helped you.
但是船上还有更多的药
But there's more medicine aboard the ship.
我会帮你，但你必须等
I'll help you, but you must wait.
你明白的，不是吗？
You do see that, don't you?
很快，史波克会来这…
Soon Spock will be here and...
史波克？
Spock?
至少我已经安排了
At least I've arranged that much.
你是怎么做到的？
How did you manage that?
告诉一个觉得我性感的守卫
A convincing lie told to a guard...
一个令人信服的谎言
who finds me desirable.
亲爱的…
Darling.
不，不，你不能阻止我！
No, no. Y-You mustn't stop me.
他是我的爱人，我必须杀了他
He's my lover and I have to kill him.
[呻吟]
[Moans]
她似乎想出了一个万无一失的方法
She seems to have worked out an infallible method
以确保男性永久的忠诚
for assuring permanent male fidelity.
有趣
Interesting.
我很高兴见到你
I'm very glad to see you.
谢谢，舰长，我们现在有武器了
Thank you, Captain. We're now armed.
我想我们应该去控制室
I presume we shall try to reach the control room.
是的，你猜得对
Yes, you presume correctly.
[咔嗒声]
[Click]
力场关着，舰长
Force field is now off, Captain.
柯克呼叫企业号，柯克呼叫企业号
Kirk to Enterprise. Kirk to Enterprise.
斯科特先生，我是舰长
Mr. Scott, it's the captain.
我是斯科特，舰长，你让我们担心了
Scott here, Captain. You had us worried.
斯科特先生，我想要立刻传送一支武装特遣队下来
Mr. Scott, I want a fully armed security detail beamed down on the double.
他们已经在传送室了，长官
They're already in the transporter room, sir.
并让麦考伊医生尽快准备额外的药物
And have Dr. McCoy prepare additional medicine as quickly as possible.
是的，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
舰长，我建议你回到船上
Captain, I suggest you return to the ship at once.
你的安全对企业号至关重要
Your safety is vital to the Enterprise.
等待你的指令，舰长
Waiting for your order, Captain.
我还请求允许留在这负责警卫队
I also request permission to remain here in charge of the security team.
很好，史波克
Very well, Spock.
等待中，舰长
Still waiting, Captain.
斯科特先生，舰长的生命危在旦夕
Mr. Scott, the captain's life is in immediate danger.
把他传送上船，安全小组将委托给我
Beam him aboard at once. The security team will be entrusted to me.
女王到女王三级
Queen to queen's level three.
重复，女王到女王三级
Repeat. Queen to queen's level three.
他在等待正确的答复，舰长
He's waiting for the proper reply, Captain.
[斯科提] 按顺序给出暗号
[Scotty] Give the countersign as ordered.
斯科提，史波克先生会给出暗号
Scotty, Mr. Spock will give the countersign.
给他暗号，舰长
Give him the countersign, Captain.
[斯科提] 安全特遣队，准备好传送下去
[Scotty] Security detail, standby to beam down.
开枪，舰长，如果你能的话
Blast away, Captain, if you can.
你以为我会傻到给你充电的相位枪吗？
Do you think I'm fool enough to give you a charged phaser?
你对史波克做了什么？他在哪儿？
What have you done with Spock? Where is he?
我还没有对他做任何事，但我确实对他有计划
I have done nothing with him yet, but I do have plans for him.
瓦肯人会死得很惨，他的死将取决于你的良心
The Vulcan will die horribly, and his death will be on your conscience.
加斯舰长…
Captain Garth-
加斯勋爵！
Lord Garth!
不，长官
No, sir.
加斯舰长
Captain Garth,
星际舰队舰长
star ship fleet captain.
这是一个光荣的称号
That's an honourable title.
我是他们中最伟大的，不是吗？
And I was the greatest of them all, wasn't I?
对，你是
Yes, you were.
是的
Yes.
但你现在是个病人，长官
But you're a sick man now, sir.
我从未如此健康
I have never been more healthy.
不，不，想想
No. No, think.
sdfad
回想一下你是谁
Think back to what you were...
在导致你去安托斯四号的事故前
before the accident that sent you to Antos IV.
试试
Try.
我不记得了，就好像我死了又重生了一样
I can't remember. It's almost as if I had died and was reborn.
不，我…我记得
No, I-I can remember.
你…
You...
是学院最优秀的学生
were the finest student at the academy,
最优秀的星舰舰长
the finest star ship captain.
你是模范，我们其他人的榜样
You were the prototype, the model for the rest of us.
是的，我确实记得
Yes, I do remember that.
那是一项重大的责任
It was a great responsibility,
但我很自豪能够承担
but one I was proud to bear.
你表现得很好
And you bore it well.
疾病改变了你
And the disease that changed you,
那不是你的错
it's not your fault.
从那以后你所做的可怕的事情，并不是你的责任
And the terrible things you did since then, not truly responsible.
我不想再听了，你很软弱
I don't want to hear any more. You're weak,
你试图耗尽我的力量
and trying to drain my strength.
不，我没有
No, I'm not.
我想要你找到你曾经拥有的
I want you to find what you once had,
我想要你回溯你失去的伟大，加斯舰长
I want you to go back to the greatness that you've lost, Captain Garth.
我是加斯勋爵！
I am Lord Garth!
宇宙之主
Master of the universe!
你怀疑我，因为我还没有加冕
You doubt me because I have not yet had my coronation.
不，长官，听我说，我
No, sir, listen to me. I-
停！
Stop!
跪下
On your knees.
不
No.
给我跪下！
On your knees before me!
在我之前的所有其他人都失败了
All the others before me have failed--
亚历山大、凯撒、拿破仑、
Alexander, Caesar, Napoleon,
希特勒、李光、克罗图斯！
Hitler, Lee Kuan, Krotus!
他们都化作了尘土！
All of them are dust!
但我会胜利的
But I will triumph!
我会做出最终的征服！
I will make the ultimate conquest!
宝座必须更高
The throne must be higher.
它一定要比这个房间里的任何东西都高
It must be higher than anything else in this room.
唔，把那张桌子当底座
Mmm, use that table as a pedestal.
啊，欢迎回来，柯克舰长
Ah, welcome back, Captain Kirk.
我很高兴你能参加加冕典礼
I'm glad you could make it for the coronation.
加冕？
Coronation?
是的，哦，我知道，即使是真正的宝座也只不过是一把椅子
Yes. Oh, I know that even a real throne is no more than merely a chair,
但象征意义很重要，你不同意吗？
but the symbolism is important, don't you agree?
是的我同意，我想你也会戴上皇冠的
Yes, I agree. You'll wear a crown too, I presume?
但同样，只是一个象征
But again, just as a token.
但它可以作为旗帜，召集我们的追随者
It will serve as a standard around which our followers will rally.
加斯，你只有几个手下
Garth, you have only a handful of men.
你真的拒绝参与这件事，不是吗，舰长？
You do refuse to enter into the spirit of the thing, don't you, Captain?
也许你想在仪式中扮演更重要的角色
Perhaps you'd like a larger role in the ceremony.
你可以充当人类祭品
You could serve as human sacrifice.
不，我一点也不会享受
No, I wouldn't enjoy that at all.
再说，你好像需要我活着
Besides, you seem to need me alive.
不错，那么，呃…
How true. All right, uh...
储君怎么样？
how about crown prince?
那会让你成为我们的继承人
That would make you our heir apparent.
继承人，我相信这是适合你的角色
Heir apparent, I believe, is the proper role for you.
此外，我们还有其他的人类祭品候选人
Besides, we have other candidates for our human sacrifice.
谁知道呢？我们准备好了
Who knows? Ready.
嗯，既然没有足够强大的人来主持这个仪式
Well, since there is no one mighty enough to perform this ceremony,
我就自己主持
we'll perform it ourselves.
因此，我在此宣布我是
Therefore, we hereby proclaim that I am...
加斯勋爵，宇宙的主人
Lord Garth, master of the universe.
我指定我心爱的玛塔
And we designate our beloved Marta...
为我的配偶
to be our consort.
我进一步指定企业号的柯克舰长
And we further designate Captain James Kirk of the star ship Enterprise...
为我的继承人
to be our heir apparent.
现在把我的继承人带走
Let's now remove our heir apparent,
我就可以结束这场仪式了
that we may conclude this ceremony.
[开门]
[Door Opens]
听我说，这可能是我们最后的机会了…
Listen to me. This may be our last chance...
加斯会毁了我们所有人，除非你们帮我阻止他
Garth will destroy all of us unless you help me stop him.
他在利用你们，知道吗，因为他想要自己拥有权力
And he's using you, you know, because he wants the power for himself.
我带来了一些本可能治愈你们的东西，但被他摧毁了
I brought something that might have cured you, but he destroyed it.
如果我让一支巡逻队下来，他们会带更多的...哦！
If I can get a patrol down, they'd bring more-Oh!
做得好
Well done.
好吧，舰长，你继续反抗
Well, Captain, you continue to resist.
你真蠢
How stupid of you.
把他放在这把椅子上
Put him in that chair right here.
我安排了一个小节目
I've arranged a small entertainment.
我不想让他错过任何细节
I wouldn't want him to miss any of it.
舰长，连你都得承认我是个天才
Well, Captain, even you must admit that I'm a genius.
你看到的是我的最新发明
What you see here is my latest invention.
这是一个炸药
This is an explosive,
史上最强的
the most powerful one in history.
如果我丢下这个烧瓶
If I were to drop this flask,
由此产生的爆炸会使这个星球蒸发
the resulting explosion would vaporize this planet.
现在，你明白为什么抵抗我是荒谬的了吗，舰长？
Now do you see why it is ridiculous to resist me, Captain?
好吧，也许你需要
Well, perhaps you require...
我安排的演示
the demonstration I've arranged.
盯紧了
Watch closely.
的确，她像毒蛇一样致命
Now, it is true that she is deadly as a poisonous serpent:
但她也是一个美丽的女人
but she is also a beautiful woman,
你曾经抱她在你的怀里，舰长
and you have held her in your arms, Captain.
我命令我的人把她赶出防护罩
I've ordered my men to drive her out of the protective dome.
当然，几分钟后她会在外面窒息而死
And, of course, she would choke to death on the outside in minutes,
但我为她安排了一个更仁慈的结局
but I've arranged a more merciful end for her...
因为，毕竟，舰长，她是我的配偶
because after all, Captain, she is my consort.
她的项链中植入了一颗微小的晶体
One tiny crystal implanted in her necklace,
一份这种炸药比一粒沙子还小
a portion of this explosive no bigger than a grain of sand.
我打算从这里引爆它
I propose to detonate it from here.
可怜的姑娘
Oh, poor girl.
可怜的受苦受难的孩子
Poor, dear, suffering child.
我现在就帮她
I will help her now.
厄尔巴二号上发生了爆炸
There's been an explosion on Elba Il!
.95
Point nine five!
它一定已经抹除了一切
It must've wiped out everything!
立即探测！力场还在吗，苏鲁先生？
Immediate probe! Is the force field in place, Mr. Sulu?
是的，长官，很坚固
Yes, sir. Solidly.
生命继续存在于这个星球上
Life continues to exist on the planet.
必须以某种方式突围
Got to break through it somehow!
医生
Doctor,
我告诉过你，我们做不到，除非杀死庇护所穹顶中的所有人
I told you we couldn't do it without killing everyone in the asylum dome.
我知道，斯科提
I know it, Scotty.
好吧，最后有件事我们可以试一下
Well, there's one last thing we might try.
也许飞船的相位炮可以在最薄弱的地方切开力场
Perhaps the ship's phasers can cut through a section of the forcefield at its weakest point.
你之前说它在哪里？
Where did you say that was located?
在星球的另一侧
On the far side of the planet.
它会为下面的人留下安全距离吗？
Will it leave a margin of safety for the people below?
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
准备改变轨道，苏鲁先生
Prepare to change orbital path, Mr. Sulu.
解除轨道坐标
Orbital coordinates released, sir.
终止同步轨道,前往航线14，标记68
Break synchronous orbit. Come to course 14 mark 68.
航线14，标记68
Course 14 mark 68.
重新建立同步轨道，长官
Synchronous orbit re-established, sir.
飞船相位炮调到窄波束
Ship's phasers to narrow beam.
飞船相位炮准备好了，长官
Ship's phasers ready, sir.
让我们在上面打个洞，全功率
Let's punch a hole in it. Full power.
再来一次，全功率
Another blast, full power.
力场还在，长官
Force field's still holding, sir.
接着
Here.
[加斯笑]
[Garth Laughing]
柯克，你觉得经怎么样？
How are your nerves, Kirk?
我只能说，加斯，如果它发生在我身上，它也会发生在你身上
All I can say, Garth, if it happens to me, it happens to you.
你真是一个特别的家伙，柯克
You're an extraordinary fellow, Kirk.
你的固执违背了所有的逻辑
Your stubbornness defies all logic.
逻辑，这就是关键
Logic, that is the key.
你的朋友史波克是个有逻辑的人
Your friend Spock is a logical man.
一个很有逻辑的人
A very logical man.
去把瓦肯人带到我这里来
Go and bring the Vulcan here to me.
[电流噼啪声]
[Electrical Crackling]
[咔嗒声]
[Click]
史波克不仅比你更有逻辑，舰长
Spock is not only a more logical man than you, Captain,
而且是一个更聪明的人，我肯定
he's a more intelligent one, I'm sure.
我将与他建立融洽的关系
I shall establish a rapport with him.
[哔哔声]
[Beeping]
[咔嗒声]
[Click]
真有趣
Fascinating.
你的瓦肯朋友是一个非常机敏的家伙，这可能是最有趣的
Your Vulcan friend is a very ingenious fellow. This could be most amusing.
那是加斯，击晕他
That's Garth. Stun him.
别开枪，史波克，那是加斯
Hold it, Spock! That's Garth!
仔细看看我，史波克，你看不出来我是你的舰长吗？
Look at me carefully, Spock. Can't you tell I'm your captain?
女王到女王三级
Queen to queen's level three.
我不会回答，这就是他想知道的
I won't answer that. That's exactly what he wants to know.
非常聪明，加斯，这正是我要说的
Very clever, Garth. That's exactly what I was going to say.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
安排传送一支安全小队下来，有异议吗？
Arranging to beam down a security team. Are there any objections?
是的，他们可能会陷入陷阱
Yes. They may walk into a trap.
没错，加斯能摧毁我们
That's right. Garth can destroy us.
真有趣
Fascinating.
我们用什么策略
What maneuver did we use...
在天仓五附近打败了罗慕伦飞船？
to defeat the Romulan vessel near Tau Ceti?
非常好，史波克，科克伦减速
Very good, Spock. The Cochran deceleration.
史波克，你知道……
Spock, you know...
科克伦减速是经典的战斗策略
the Cochran deceleration's a classic battle maneuver.
每个星舰舰长都知道这一点
Every star ship captain knows that.
同意，舰长
Agreed, Captain.
舰长们
Captains.
先生们，无论你们中的哪一个是加斯舰长
Gentlemen, whichever one of you is Captain Garth...
都必须花费大量精力来维持柯克舰长的形象
must be expending a great deal of energy to maintain the image of Captain Kirk.
这种能量水平不能无限期地保持
That energy level cannot be maintained indefinitely,
而我有时间
and I have time.
我是你的舰长，史波克！你看不出来吗？开枪，开枪！
I'm your captain, Spock! Can't you tell? Shoot. Shoot!
他是对的，史波克，你必须开枪，但你必须朝我们俩开枪
He's right, Spock, you must shoot. But you must shoot both of us.
这是确保企业号安全的唯一途径
It's the only way to ensure the safety of the Enterprise.
我猜你是柯克舰长
Captain Kirk, I presume.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
史波克呼叫企业号
Spock to Enterprise.
[斯科提] 这里是企业号
[Scotty] Enterprise here.
女王到女王三级
Queen to queen's level three.
女王到国王一级
Queen to king's level one.
肌内注射可以吗？
Will intramuscular injection be satisfactory?
除非条件不允许，否则需要静脉注射
Intravenous is indicated unless circumstances make it impossible.
麦考伊医生，多久生效？
How long before it takes effect, Dr. McCoy?
动脉和脑损伤的逆转应立即开始
Reversal of arterial and brain damage should begin almost immediately.
[低沉的嗡嗡声]
[Low-Pitched Whirring]
[咔嗒声]
[Click]
[嗡嗡声停止]
[Whirring Stops]
加斯舰长，我是詹姆斯·柯克
Captain Garth, I'm James Kirk.
我是史波克先生
I am Mr. Spock,
星舰上的科学官
science officer on a star ship.
星舰企业号
The star ship Enterprise.
星舰？
Star ship?
是的，长官，企业号，我是舰长
Yes, sir, the Enterprise. I'm the captain.
我能帮你吗？
Can I help you?
不，舰长，药似乎起效了
No, Captain. The medicine seems to be taking effect.
我应付得了，这是非常令人鼓舞的
I can manage. It's very encouraging.
先生，我应该认识你吗？
Should I know you, sir?
不，舰长，不
No, Captain. No.
史波克先生  是的，舰长
Mr. Spock. Yes, Captain.
告诉我，为什么无法分辨我们之间的区别？
Tell me, why was it so impossible to tell the difference between us?
并非不可能，舰长
It was not impossible, Captain.
我们在这里的存在证明了这一点
Our presence here is proof of that.
是的，恭喜
Yes, and congratulations.
你怎么花了这么久？
What took you so long?
不确定的间隔实际上相当短，舰长
The interval of uncertainty was actually fairly brief, Captain.
只是对你来说似乎很长
It only seemed long to you.
我在等待打斗的胜利者
I was waiting for a victor in the struggle,
我假定会是加斯舰长
which I assumed would be Captain Garth.
因为你的状况不佳
Because of your depleted condition.
未能解决打斗
Failing a resolution to the struggle,
我被迫使用其他方式来做出决定
I was forced to use other means to make my determination.
我知道了
I see.
史波克先生，唔
Mr. Spock, um,
让自己被击中头部
letting yourself be hit on the head,
我猜你让自己被击中了头部
and I presume you let yourself be hit on the head,
这完全不像聪明人会想出来的方法
is not exactly a method King Solomon would have approved.
斯科特先生，准备好传送上船
Mr. Scott, ready to beam up.
是的，长官
Aye, aye, sir.